Hello, everyone.
大家好。
So welcome.
非常欢迎。
We are going to continue our lecture on a virtual memory.
我们将继续进行关于虚拟内存的讲座。
We are going to start discussion on caching and tlb so it's time for the translation.
我们将开始讨论缓存和TLB，所以现在是翻译的时候了。
Look aside buffers.
旁路缓冲区
So if you recall,
所以如果你还记得的话，
address translation,
地址转换
as a name implies,
正如其名所示，
it's about translating the addresses which are viewed by the application
这是关于将应用程序查看的地址进行翻译的问题。
by the cp us into physical addresses.
通过将CPU转换为物理地址。
There are a couple of reasons why we want to have this different kind of
有几个原因我们想要有这种不同类型的方式
addresses for the application and versus of the physical
应用程序的地址和物理地址的对比
addresses.
地址。
Some of them are about providing the illusion to each application.
其中一些问题涉及为每个应用程序提供幻觉。
It has its own machine,
它有自己的机器。
its own resources,
自己的资源
including the memory,
包括内存在内，
which means that then you need to map the address space of each
这意味着你需要映射每个地址空间。
of the application in the same physical space,
在同一物理空间中的应用程序
which is physical memory.
物理内存是指计算机系统中实际存在的内存硬件。
And also,
而且，
another reason is protection,
另一个原因是保护性。
because you want to protect the address space and of one application from another,
因为你想要保护一个应用程序的地址空间不受其他应用程序的影响。
and also sharing, control, sharing, if you remember,
还有共享、控制、共享，如果你还记得的话。
in which actually some parts of the address space you want to be shared.
你希望在实际上共享地址空间的某些部分。
For instance,
例如，
the address space which contains a code of a shared library of a library,
包含库的共享库代码的地址空间
which is a code of a library,
这是一个库的代码。
which is used by two applications like windows library on your own windows machine.
这是在你自己的Windows机器上，两个应用程序使用的类似于Windows库的功能。
You do not want, but it begins that code in each application.
你不想要，但每个应用程序都会开始那段代码。
You want to share that.
你想分享那个。
Typically, you do the sharing.
通常情况下，您进行共享。
It happens.
没关系。
It's handled by one of these components are cheap,
其中一个组件是廉价的，它会处理这个问题。
which is called a lot of this memory management unit.
这被称为内存管理单元。
This was originally a a a was a standalone chip,
这最初是一个独立的芯片。
which is you put near your between the processor and the memory.
在处理器和内存之间，你应该放置什么？
But in the more than processors,
但在多处理器系统中，
it just a component of that processor.
它只是该处理器的一个组件。
One of the modest one of the techniques to do address translation was
其中一种较为简单的地址转换技术是
a segment using multi segment.
使用多段的分段。
And in this case, if you remember,
在这种情况下，如果你还记得的话，
reach a segment is represented by a base and a limit.
一个段的表示由基址和限长组成。
Okay?
好的？
Now, the visual,
现在，视觉化，
the address, which our address is against the address,
地址，我们的地址与该地址相对立。
which is seen by the cpu and is seen by the application.
这是CPU所看到的，也是应用程序所看到的。
We split into two,
我们分成两组，
the first part of the first few beats represent an index in the segment table.
第一部分的前几个节拍代表段表中的索引。
And then there is an opposite.
然后还有一个相反的情况。
Okay?
好的？
When you have a virtual address,
当你有一个虚拟地址时，
you look at the first field,
你看一下第一个字段，
which is the segment number.
这是段号。
The first speech represent the second number,
第一个演讲代表第二个数字。
use up to index into segment table.
使用索引访问段表。
And then in that segment table,
然后在那个段表中，
you are going to find the base of the segment and the limit.
你需要找到该段的基址和限制。
And you are going to compute the physical address by adding the offset,
然后你将通过添加偏移量来计算物理地址。
which is the second giving the virtual address to the segment base.
第二种方式是将虚拟地址赋值给段基址。
These are the address.
这些是地址。
And you are also going to check whether the address is generated is
而且你还要检查生成的地址是否正确
less than the limit.
小于限制。
So it's within the segment.
所以它在段内。
You also have in some architecture, actually,
在某些体系结构中，你也有这样的情况。
in intel eight x 86.
在英特尔的x86架构中。
Instead of having the first the beats in the virtual address,
不再将虚拟地址中的第一个字节作为开头。
presenting the the base,
呈现基础部分，
the indexing into the segment table,
对段表进行索引
you have just a bunch of segments,
你只有一堆段落。
you have the initial,
你有初始值。
you have four segments.
你有四个段。
And these segments are men,
这些片段是男性。
are base segments,
基本段
are stored in special registers.
被存储在特殊寄存器中。
Like es this is s is for the stack and three other registers.
这是关于栈和其他三个寄存器的说明。
Then you compute the address by taking the virtual address,
然后你通过获取虚拟地址来计算地址。
and you are going to add it to the segment register.
你需要将它添加到段寄存器中。
That's how you are going to compute the physical address.
这是你计算物理地址的方法。
A finally, there is a bit valid or not valid.
最后，有一个位是有效的还是无效的。
This one is at the segment,
这个位于段落中。
not all segments of all application can fit in the physical memory
并非所有应用程序的所有段都能适应物理内存。
at the same time.
同时。
So when you run out of space in the physical memory,
当物理内存空间不足时，
and you want to load,
而且你想要加载，
you start a new application on your program that it needs to.
你在程序上启动了一个新的应用程序，它需要...
You need to allocate spacing.
你需要分配空间。
The physical memory presenting program is a segment, is a new program.
物理内存展示程序是一个段，是一个新的程序。
You may take one of the existing segments of an application.
您可以使用应用程序中的一个现有段落。
It doesn't run, and we are going to store it on the disk.
它无法运行，我们打算将其存储在磁盘上。
Okay?
好的？
Then therefore, the segment is no longer in memory.
因此，该段不再在内存中。
So then you can say it's you can use this bit to specify that.
那么你可以说，你可以使用这个位来指定。
So whenever next time,
所以下次无论何时，
when you are looking for something in that segment,
当你在那个段落中寻找某个东西时，
then you are going to you are going to get an exception,
那么你将会收到一个异常。
and the exception is going to be treated by the operating system.
异常将由操作系统处理。
The operating system will bring the segment from the disk to memory
操作系统将从磁盘将段加载到内存中。
before executing that instruction.
在执行该指令之前。
This is some examples.
这是一些例子。
Here.
在这里。
It's a simple.
这很简单。
An example of an architecture is four segments.
一个架构的例子是四个段。
The address is 16 bits.
地址是16位的。
The first 2 bits of the address are used to specify the segment number,
地址的前两位用于指定段号。
because we have four segments.
因为我们有四个段。
We need only to be.
我们只需要存在。
So this at least 15 and 14.
至少是15和14。
The rest of these from 13 to 0 represent the office.
从13到0的剩余部分代表办公室。
On the left hand side, you can see the address space,
在左侧，您可以看到地址空间。
the virtual address space.
虚拟地址空间。
So as seen by the application,
从应用程序的角度来看，
we have our traditional four segments,
我们有我们传统的四个段，
a code segments,
一个代码段
the data,
数据
the stack segments.
栈段。
This is also we added a shared segment.
这也是我们添加了一个共享段。
Think about this is either that 8 hours a code,
考虑一下，这可能是每天编码8小时的情况。
which you may want to share with another application.
这些信息可能需要与另一个应用程序共享。
So here with in green,
这里是绿色的。
you have the table,
你有这张表。
the segment table,
段表
again, four entries for code data shared and the stack.
再次，对于代码、数据、共享和栈，有四个条目。
And you have the base and the limit for each of these segments.
你有每个段的基址和限长。
Now,
现在，
let's see what happens,
让我们看看会发生什么，
for instance, and on the right hand side,
例如，在右侧。
you have the physical address.
你有物理地址。
For simply things like, in this case,
对于简单的事情，比如在这种情况下，
the physical address and the virtual address spaces,
物理地址和虚拟地址空间
they have the same size.
它们的大小相同。
Say, you are going from the code,
你正在从代码中进行操作。
you are going to execute in instruction in the code.
你将要执行代码中的一条指令。
Where is that going to be mapped in the physical address space?
这将被映射到物理地址空间的哪个位置？
If you look about in the segment table,
如果你在段表中查找，
because the first two beats of everything in the code segment at zero.
因为代码段中的所有内容的前两个节拍都是零。
Therefore, you are going to identify the first entry,
因此，你将要识别第一个条目。
right?
对的？
In the segment table,
在段表中，
you have a base of four salad in hex,
你有一个以十六进制表示的四个沙拉的基数。
a specimen format.
一个样本格式。
Therefore, you have to add an 4,000 to every address,
因此，您需要将每个地址增加4,000。
a virtual address is a code segment.
虚拟地址是一个代码段。
And to get the physical responding,
为了获得物理响应，
physical address for the code in the physical outer space,
物理外部空间中代码的物理地址
then for data,
那么对于数据来说，
the data starts in the visual of the space at 4,000.
数据从空间的可视化开始，位于4,000处。
This means that what are the first two beats of any address in the data segment?
这意味着在数据段中，任何地址的前两个字节是什么？
Why don't you tell me?
为什么你不告诉我呢？
It should be a very simple answer here.
这应该是一个非常简单的答案。
The first we have 16 bits when we use a hexadecimal representation,
当我们使用十六进制表示时，首先我们有16位。
right?
对的吗？
4 bits represent one digit.
4位表示一个数字。
Now we have four here for us.
现在我们这里有四个人。
What does it mean?
这句话的意思是什么？
What are the forbes?
福布斯是一家美国的商业杂志和媒体公司，成立于1917年。福布斯以发布全球富豪榜而闻名，该榜单列出了世界上最富有的人。此外，福布斯还报道商业、投资、科技、创业和领导力等领域的新闻和文章。福布斯也是一个知名的品牌，拥有多个国际版本和在线平台。
The first forbids,
第一个禁止，
the forbids representing the 4th.
禁止代表第四个。
How do you write for in binary presentation?
你如何用二进制表示"for"这个词？
Here it is.
这是它。
I'm writing this in our chat,
我正在我们的聊天中写这个。
foreign binary representation.
外部二进制表示。
If you want to represent it,
如果你想要表示它，
or in using 4 bits is 10100.
或者使用4位二进制表示为10100。
This is it, right?
是这样的，对吗？
It's 100 is 4 in the binary presentation,
在二进制表示中，100等于4。
which means that the first beats for any address in the beta segment.
这意味着beta段中的任何地址的第一个字节。
The segment number here is what?
这里的段号是什么？
01.
01. 欢迎来到CS162计算机操作系统课程！我是你的助教。如果你有任何问题或需要帮助，请随时向我提问。
Now it's not 00101,
现在不是00101了。
because it's only the first to beat,
因为它只是第一个被击败的。
but it is for its product.
但这是针对它的产品。
It can go, okay,
可以，好的。
it's 01.
现在是01点。
This is what is one?
这是什么意思？
This is what you have.
这是你所拥有的。
Therefore, to translate any address in the data segment.
因此，要将数据段中的任何地址进行翻译。
What do you need to?
你需要什么帮助？
Do you go to the second entry in the segment table?
你是否要进入段表的第二个条目？
The one, which the segment id number is one,
其中段号为1的那个
and the base here is 4,800.
这里的基数是4,800。
So what you need to do is that you are going to add,
你需要做的是添加，
in order to translate any address in the data segment,
为了翻译数据段中的任何地址，
you need to add to it for the 800
你需要为800添加一些内容。
for the shared segment.
对于共享段。
This is the things go.
事情就是这样进行的。
This similarly,
同样地，
for the share of settlement,
关于结算的分享，
they started 800,000.
他们开始了80万。
So the first four beats is eight,
所以前四拍是八拍。
represent eight.
表示数字八。
What is the binary presentation of eight?
八的二进制表示是 1000。
It's exactly.
没错。
The first two beats at 10.
前两拍速度为10。
The second one number,
第二个数字，
one, it's 10 is two.
一，它是10，是二。
Right?
对吗？
Because you take only the first two beats.
因为你只取前两拍。
And finally, stack c what is ac the representation?
最后，栈 c 的表示是什么？
Binary representation of c you should remember this.
你应该记住 c 的二进制表示。
Right?
对吗？
Is the review.
这是一篇评论。
It's 1100.
现在是1100点。
Exactly, very good.
没错，非常好。
The first two bits are 11.
前两位是11。
It's three.
现在是三点钟。
Number three is the last entry in the table.
第三个是表格中的最后一项。
And for go to the stack,
而要进入栈，
the base is zero, right?
基数是零，对吗？
You add the base offset to the base.
你将基址偏移量加到基址上。
We started from 000.
我们从000开始。
Does it make sense?
这有意义吗？
Let's look at this as an example.
让我们以这个作为例子来看。
By the way,
顺便说一下，
you should you should try.
你应该尝试一下。
These are some very important slides,
这些是一些非常重要的幻灯片，
because you may expect not only to understand how the address translation works,
因为你可能希望不仅了解地址转换的工作原理，
which is one of the fundamental mechanics in used in the existing
这是现有系统中使用的基本机制之一。
in today's processors and leverage
在今天的处理器中利用和发挥作用
by the operating system to provide virtual memory,
通过操作系统提供虚拟内存，
abstraction,
抽象化
but also because you can expect problems like this in your next meter.
而且因为你可以预料到你下一个计量器会出现类似的问题。
Okay.
好的。
Now, let's look at this piece of code and see what happens under the foot.
现在，让我们来看看这段代码，在底层发生了什么。
And we are assuming this piece of code is going to run
我们假设这段代码将会运行。
on the previous architecture from.
在先前的架构上。
Ii just showed you in the last slide,
我刚在上一张幻灯片中给你展示了。
you have the segment table is the same.
你有相同的段表。
Now is a code.
现在是一段代码。
The code starts that to 40.
代码从40开始。
We don't basically the entire address is 0240,
我们的基本地址是0240。
but you don't show the first four beats which are zero.
但你没有显示前四个节拍，它们都是零。
Okay.
好的。
Now let's see what happens.
现在让我们看看会发生什么。
And this is a serial language,
这是一种串行语言，
theodore assembly, language, code.
Theodore汇编语言代码。
Let's see what happens when we start with the disco.
让我们看看从迪斯科开始会发生什么。
The first instruction is a main,
第一条指令是一个主函数。
and basically what his instruction is doing.
基本上，他的指令是在做什么。
It loads an address which is bar x into register a
它将一个地址 bar x 加载到寄存器 a 中。
zero right now,
零，现在。
this code is run in the user process,
这段代码在用户进程中运行。
the user process.
用户进程。
See virtual addresses.
查看虚拟地址。
So all the addresses you see here are virtual addresses.
这里看到的所有地址都是虚拟地址。
Okay?
好的？
But now the code and the data they are actually stored in the physical memory
但是现在代码和数据实际上存储在物理内存中。
in order to read the instructions and access a data,
为了阅读说明并访问数据，
we need to translate the virtual addresses to the physical address.
我们需要将虚拟地址转换为物理地址。
So they address the instruction, firstly,
首先，他们解析指令。
to fetch the instruction in order to execute the instructions instruction.
为了执行指令，需要获取指令。
Again, it's in physical memory.
再次强调，它存储在物理内存中。
The address of virtual address,
虚拟地址的地址
it's 0~40.
是0到40。
We discussed.
我们讨论了。
Here is a binary representation of the address.
这是一个地址的二进制表示。
The first to beat are zero.
首先要击败的是零。
The segment id the sigma number is zero.
该段的Sigma编号为零。
Is that a four in order,
这是按顺序的四个吗？
translate this address for virtual address to 40,
将虚拟地址转换为物理地址为40。
to a physical address,
到物理地址，
we need to add the base address corresponding to the segment.
我们需要添加与段对应的基地址。
So the basis 4,000 and the virtual offset,
所以基址是4,000，虚拟偏移量是...
right?
对的？
Is 240.
是240。
The virtual officers.
虚拟官员。
The offset is the other side of the black beats.
偏移量是黑色节拍的另一侧。
In the address,
在地址中，
the beats encoding,
Beats编码
the segment identifier are the green beats.
段标识符是绿色的节拍。
Obviously,
显然，
you have to add all the offset,
你需要将所有的偏移量相加。
which is 240 to 4,000,
这是从240到4,000。
which is a base.
哪一个是基数。
And therefore, you are going to get the physical address 4,000, 200, 40.
因此，您将获得物理地址 4,000、200、40。
Now,
现在，
you are going to use this address to fetch the instruction from the memory.
你将使用这个地址从内存中获取指令。
And the instruction is basically like I told you,
指令基本上就像我告诉你的那样。
it's to load the address,
这是为了加载地址。
which is barracks address,
请问是哪个兵营的地址？
which is 4050 is the virtual address into a registration.
将4050作为虚拟地址加载到寄存器中。
Now, after that,
现在，在那之后，
you execute the instruction, you would know very well.
你执行这条指令，你会非常清楚。
What happens next?
接下来会发生什么？
The program counter.
程序计数器。
It's increment by four,
它每次增加四，
because he are assuming that there are instruction,
因为他假设存在指令。
they occupy 4 bytes.
它们占据4个字节。
The next instruction address is 2, 44.
下一条指令的地址是2, 44。
So let's execute the next instruction.
那么让我们执行下一条指令。
It's again,
又是这样，
in the next instruction,
在下一条指令中，
you are going to see you have now the other sister for,
你将会看到，你现在有了另一个姐妹。
like I mentioned,
就像我之前提到的那样，
again, the physical,
再次，物理层
if you look at,
如果你看一下，
this will also be in the code segment,
这也将位于代码段中，
we need to add the base, which is 4,000.
我们需要加上基数，即4,000。
The physical address would be 4244.
物理地址将是4244。
You are going to get the next instruction,
你将要获取下一条指令。
which is jail to jam to this string,
将这个字符串压缩到哪个目录下？
land address,
土地地址
label.
标签。
All right?
好吗？
And this is exactly what you do it.
这就是你所做的。
But before the jumping here,
但在此之前，
we store the return address.
我们存储返回地址。
After we execute the function string land,
执行完函数string land之后，
we need to return, well,
我们需要返回，嗯，
to the next instruction after the jump,
跳转指令后的下一条指令
the next instruction after the jump would be zero,
跳转指令之后的下一条指令将是零。
x 248.
Therefore, we are going to,
因此，我们打算，
we assume here that we have a return address registers,
我们在这里假设我们有一个返回地址寄存器。
Which stores the return address.
存储返回地址的是什么？
So we are going to load into the return address,
所以我们将加载到返回地址中，
0248.
And this is done automatically by the compiled code,
这是由编译后的代码自动完成的。
by your obligation.
根据你的义务。
Then you move in the priest program,
然后你进入了牧师程序。
counter the address,
计数器地址
or you want to jump.
或者你想跳跃。
So the address you want to jump,
所以你想要跳转的地址是，
the label string line is corresponding to the address360.
标签字符串行对应于地址360。
So you're going to jump there,
所以你要跳过去，
and you are going to execute that next instruction,
然后你将执行下一条指令。
which will be the address 360360.
地址360360将是什么？
Its, again, is in the segment code.
这个问题再次出现在代码段中。
In order to compute the physical address,
为了计算物理地址，
you are going towards the base,
你正在朝基地前进。
which is 4,000 of 4,000+360,
4,000占4,000+360的比例是多少？
is 400, 660.
是 400，660。
And then you are going to read from the physical memory.
然后你将从物理内存中读取数据。
You are going to read,
你将要阅读的是，
and this instruction is basically initialize this account, put a zero,
这个指令基本上是初始化这个账户，将其设为零。
a in a register v zero.
将 a 存储在寄存器 v zero 中。
Once you execute that to go to the next instruction,
执行该指令后，进入下一条指令。
and the next instruction,
下一条指令是，
the other is 364.
另一个是364。
And this next instruction,
而这个下一条指令，
it loads what is at this particular address,
它加载了这个特定地址上的内容，
which is stored in a zero?
存储在零中的是什么？
Remember that what is stored in the a zero?
记住，零存储的是什么？
It was bar x address.
这是一个地址为x的酒吧。
This is a bar x address is 4050.
这是一个酒吧，地址是4050。
Now we are one to load in register t zero.
现在我们要将数据加载到寄存器 t zero 中。
The content of the address barracks of the address 4050.
地址4050处的地址营房的内容。
When we want to do that and we want to access it,
当我们想要做那件事并且想要访问它时，
to see what is the content of that mutual address.
查看该共享地址的内容。
The mutual address is 4050.
相互地址是4050。
This is a binary representation.
这是一个二进制表示。
The first two beats are 01.
前两拍是01。
The segment index,
段索引
which corresponds to this address is one.
对应于该地址的值为1。
Therefore, the base address of that segment is840 800.
因此，该段的基地址是840 800。
Therefore, you need to add the 4,800 to what?
因此，你需要将4,800加到什么上面？
To the offset.
到偏移量。
So what is the offset here?
这里的偏移量是什么？
The offset here, notice is 50.
这里的偏移量是50。
The virtual address is 4050.
虚拟地址为4050。
But remember,
但是请记住，
the first 2 bits of this address represent the segment id that's one.
这个地址的前两位表示段标识符为1。
And the last, in this case,
最后，在这种情况下，
14 beats represents the opposite,
14拍代表相反的意思。
but the last 14 beats is 50.
但最后14拍是50。
Now is the offset is 50.
现在的偏移量是50。
It's, again, offset is a black digits,
这里，偏移量是黑色数字。
like 01.
喜欢 01.
Then you are going to add the offset to the basis,
然后你将把偏移量加到基数上。
4,800.
4,800.  (四千八百)
The physical address you are going to compute is 4,850.
你要计算的物理地址是4,850。
And you are going to load the bite from that address to d zero.
你将从该地址加载字节到d zero寄存器中。
And you increment the program count.
然后你增加程序计数器的值。
The main thing to note here that everything,
需要注意的主要事项是，一切事物都
which is in what the processor sees,
这是处理器所看到的内容。
everything,
一切事物，
what is in the registers of the processors?
处理器的寄存器中存储了什么内容？
All these are virtual addresses.
这些都是虚拟地址。
The translation happens only where you are going to access a memory.
翻译仅在您要访问内存的地方发生。
So the memory management units really sits
因此，内存管理单元实际上是坐在那里的。
between the arithmetic logical units and all the registers and the memory.
在算术逻辑单元、所有寄存器和内存之间。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
We spent quite a bit of time on this one,
我们在这个问题上花了相当多的时间，
but this is important.
但这很重要。
Please make sure that you understand this example,
请确保您理解这个例子。
as you'll see, from the previous years and previous exams,
正如你所看到的，从以往的年份和以往的考试中，
you are going to see a lot of problems like this one.
你将会遇到很多类似这样的问题。
So a few things about some segmentation.
关于分段的一些事情。
The one problem with the segmentation is nice.
分段的一个问题是很好的。
It's a very elegant solution,
这是一个非常优雅的解决方案。
but you are going to translate on every instruction,
是的，我会在每个指令上进行翻译。
everything even in fetching instruction,
包括获取指令在内的一切
access of read some data,
读取某些数据的访问权限
write some data from the node.
从节点中写入一些数据。
And virtual address space has halls, right?
虚拟地址空间有走廊吗？
Because you are not going to use everything in your visual address.
因为你不会使用到你的虚拟地址空间中的所有内容。
That's why I use a segmentation in the first part,
这就是为什么我在第一部分使用了分段的原因。
in the first thing in the first in the first place.
首先，首先，首先。
Because if you think about,
因为如果你仔细考虑一下，
if you have the code and the segment,
如果你有代码和段落，
the segment grows,
段增长。
you put the segment as a high addresses,
你将段放在高地址处。
because it grows to the smaller,
因为它逐渐变小，
grows downwards to the smaller addresses.
向较小的地址方向增长。
For instance, a data segment,
例如，数据段，
you have to be as a lower others,
你必须以低姿态对待他人，
because it's going growing up.
因为它正在不断成长。
Okay?
好的？
Whilst the stack growing down,
在栈向下增长时，
so you need to separate them and between them, there is a gap.
所以你需要将它们分开，并且它们之间有一个间隔。
Right?
对吗？
If you have segments,
如果你有分段，
if you don't have the gap,
如果你没有间隙，
if you're sorry, if you don't have the segments,
如果你很抱歉，如果你没有这些片段，
that gap will occupy space in the physical memory.
这个间隙将占据物理内存空间。
Facebook would have been used empty space,
Facebook会利用空闲空间。
can be used to allocate to other processes,
可以用于分配给其他进程。
other applications.
其他应用程序。
However, if I have these two segments,
然而，如果我有这两个段落，
now each segment can have the one segment can have data,
现在每个段可以有一个段可以有数据。
one segment can serve the stack.
一个段可以用来作为栈。
And then they are going to be mapped on the physical memory.
然后它们将被映射到物理内存上。
The gap I don't need to map it.
这个间隙我不需要映射它。
I don't need to just waste the space on the physical memory.
我不需要浪费物理内存空间。
So now,
所以现在，
the one thing to notice here is,
这里需要注意的一件事是，
I said you are located segments for the stack and the data.
我说过你需要为栈和数据分配内存段。
But if allocate and how allocate the stack has a certain size and allocate that
但是如果分配和如何分配栈有一个确定的大小，并且分配它。
physical memory for the stack at that given size.
给定大小的堆栈的物理内存。
What happens when the stack growth and that stock growth?
当堆栈增长和栈增长时会发生什么？
Because they call more functions of, say, recursive programs.
因为它们调用了更多的函数，比如递归程序。
Every call puts the arguments and put the return values and supports
每次调用都会传递参数并返回值，并提供支持。
on the stack.
在栈上。
How do I do that?
我该怎么做呢？
Well, in the sense that when i'm going to grow the stack, for instance,
嗯，就像当我要增加栈的大小时，例如，
then i'm going to access and others outside the limit that will generate
那么我将要访问和超出限制的其他内容，这将会产生
an exception.
一个异常。
The exception will be treated by the operating system,
异常将由操作系统处理。
which is going to grow the stack.
哪个将会增加堆栈的大小。
There is a limit on modify the base and provide more room now.
现在修改基础并提供更多空间有限制。
So the program can add put more things on the stack,
所以程序可以将更多的东西放入堆栈中，
the same thing for the kids.
对于孩子们来说也是一样的。
There is a question,
有一个问题，
why did we not translate barracks in the first line on the previous slide?
为什么我们在前一张幻灯片的第一行没有翻译"barracks"这个词呢？
That's a very good question.
这是一个非常好的问题。
Why didn't translate barracks?
为什么没有翻译兵营？
Remember, what I said,
记住，我说的话，
everything is in the registers,
所有的东西都在寄存器中，
is virtual addresses.
是虚拟地址。
These are all virtual addresses,
这些都是虚拟地址。
because the rule is that the addresses are only translated when I
因为规则是只有在需要时才会进行地址转换。
am going to access a memo.
我要访问一个备忘录。
In this case, I am not accessing the memory.
在这种情况下，我没有访问内存。
Virus is just a virtual address.
病毒只是一个虚拟地址。
Right?
对吗？
I don't need to access the memory for that.
我不需要访问内存来完成这个任务。
When I need to access the memory is when i'm going to read the content
当我需要访问内存时，是因为我要读取其中的内容。
as a virtual others.
作为虚拟助教。
And then I need to call to find the corresponding physical address,
然后我需要调用函数来查找相应的物理地址。
and then on a good translation.
然后进行一个好的翻译。
But everything what is in the process,
但是一切都是在进程中的，
in the registers,
在寄存器中，
it's a virtual address space.
这是一个虚拟地址空间。
Of course, you need to put to protect the segment table.
当然，你需要保护段表。
Only the operating system has to be able to modify it.
只有操作系统才能修改它。
And also,
而且，
it provides us the operating system provides protections for different segments,
操作系统为不同的段提供保护。
for instance, to make the code segment being agreed only.
例如，使代码段仅被同意。
Now,
现在，
let's say we do a context switching.
假设我们进行一次上下文切换。
Now.
现在。
What do we need to do to say very start on contact switching when you have
当你拥有一个联系人切换时，我们需要做什么来确保非常开始？
a process context switching?
进程上下文切换
Besides that we need to to save a
除此之外，我们还需要保存一个
bunch of things like file identifiers and things like that.
一堆东西，比如文件标识符之类的东西。
The other thing we need to torn out the segment table,
另外一件事是我们需要撕毁段表。
because the segment table, as I shown, you,
因为段表，如我所示给你看的，
in the previous slide,
在前一张幻灯片中，
in the previous example,
在之前的例子中，
you have one segment table per virtual address space,
每个虚拟地址空间有一个段表。
and you have one virtual address space for the process of the application.
你的应用程序有一个虚拟地址空间。
You switch context with your process.
你通过切换进程来切换上下文。
You have also to save the segment table,
你还需要保存段表。
because the next process is going to run,
因为接下来要运行下一个进程了。
is going to have its own segment table.
将会有自己的段表。
Also, like I mentioned earlier on some of the segments of the process,
还有，就像我之前提到的进程的一些段落一样，
which is is which is no longer running,
哪一个是不再运行的？
can be stored on the disk in order to make room for the segments of the new
为了为新的段腾出空间，可以将其存储在磁盘上。
of the next process being around.
下一个进程即将到来。
Again, this is what happens is that, again,
再次，这是发生的情况，再次，
if not all segments within memory,
如果内存中没有所有的段，
you save them on the disk and you swap them.
你将它们保存在磁盘上并进行交换。
So basically,
基本上，
you say p one, c process, p one.
你说 p one, c 进程, p one.
It's is we switch from con this process beyond to be two,
我们要将这个进程从一个条件转移到另一个条件。
then we can save the segment of process p one on the disk to make room
然后我们可以将进程p的段保存在磁盘上，以腾出空间。
for the segment of process p two to be brought in the memory.
将进程p的第二个段调入内存。
If you have to do that,
如果你必须这样做，
the context switch costs will grow dramatically.
上下文切换的成本将会大幅增加。
Okay?
好的？
You need to be very careful about what you switch off or what you swap
你需要非常小心地选择关闭或交换的内容。
out and swapping on swapping,
换出和换入的交换操作，
because you really want to minimize your operation on the disk.
因为你真的想要尽量减少对磁盘的操作。
And we are going to learn about that.
我们将要学习关于这个的内容。
The next, a couple of lectures.
接下来是几节课。
Problem is fragmentation,
问题是碎片化。
problems with segmentation.
分段错误的问题。
One of the biggest problem is fragmentation,
其中一个最大的问题是碎片化。
because now you need to start a different,
因为现在你需要开始一个不同的任务。
you need to have to be able to have to store and to fit segments
你需要能够存储和适应段。
of different sizes in memory.
在内存中存储不同大小的数据块。
If you remember the last lecture,
如果你还记得上一堂课的内容，
we had an example in which you gave,
我们有一个你提供的例子。
you believe a lot of gaps.
你相信了很多空白。
You can get to a point in which you have many gaps in the physical memory,
你可能会遇到物理内存中存在许多空洞的情况。
but none of the gaps can be big enough to start a new segment,
但是这些间隙中没有一个足够大以启动一个新的段落。
rather to start a new segment.
最好开始一个新的段落。
Despite the fact that if you add them all the gap, if you add up,
尽管将它们全部相加的话，如果你把它们加起来，
all the gaps is much more than what is needed by one by that segment.
所有的间隙都比该段所需的间隙多得多。
But I think about you have 100 gaps, each gap.
但是我认为你有100个间隙，每个间隙。
It's one gigabyte.
这是一千兆字节。
You have 100 gigabytes in total of available memory.
您总共有100千兆字节的可用内存。
But now you have one segment which requires two gigabytes.
但是现在你有一个需要两个千兆字节的段。
You have plenty of available space,
你有很多可用的空间。
but none of the available spaces,
但是没有任何可用的空间，
contiguous basis.
连续基础。
It's large enough to start that segment to gigabyte segment.
这个段落足够大，可以将其划分为千兆字节的段。
So how do you do that?
那么你是如何做到的呢？
You can take one of the segments which are there to addition to one
你可以选择其中一个段落，将其加到另一个段落中。
of these one gigabyte gap.
其中有一个1GB的间隙。
And you are going to start on the disk.
你将要开始使用磁盘了。
You are swapping out to make more room,
你正在进行换页操作以腾出更多空间。
or you can move segments around.
或者你可以移动段落。
So there are 2 kinds of fragmentation.
所以有两种类型的碎片化。
Both of them were space,
它们两个都是空的。
internal fragmentation.
内部碎片化。
You don't need all the memory within allocated chunks.
你不需要使用分配块中的所有内存空间。
And this is also,
这也是的，
this is all this and then external,
这是全部的内容，然后是外部的。
which is free gaps between allocating chance.
分配机会之间的空闲间隙。
So I think this example I mentioned to you,
所以我认为我之前提到的这个例子，
I was talking about the external fragmentation.
我在谈论外部碎片化问题。
And next, we are going to talk also about internal fragmentation.
接下来，我们还要讨论内部碎片化问题。
Okay.
好的。
So basically,
基本上，
this is about another view about the general how the address translation happens.
这是关于地址转换发生的另一种观点。
This providing a little more intuition by showing two visual address
这样做可以通过展示两个可视化地址来提供更多直观的理解。
spaces mapped to the same physical address space.
将空间映射到相同的物理地址空间。
Okay?
好的？
And the these programs on and programs to or this process on and process
这些程序开启和关闭的程序，或者这个进程开启和关闭的进程。
to the virtual address spaces to each of them.
将虚拟地址空间分配给它们中的每一个。
You can look absolutely identical.
你们可以看起来完全一样。
Think about your on the same application to instances of the same application.
考虑一下你在同一个应用程序的两个实例上的情况。
But the translation,
但是翻译，
while in the virtual spaces are identical,
虽然在虚拟空间中是相同的，
you have in both virtual spaces,
你在两个虚拟空间中都有。
the same thing as the same addresses,
相同的事情就是相同的地址。
virtual addresses.
虚拟地址。
When you are going to map these virtual addresses to the physical outer space,
当你要将这些虚拟地址映射到物理地址空间时，
when you are going to translate them,
当你准备好翻译时，
you are going to translate in such a way that they are not going to conflict.
你要翻译的方式是确保它们不会产生冲突。
So now, with segmentation,
现在，使用分段技术，
we have this with external fragmentation.
我们遇到了外部碎片化的问题。
Sometimes it's harder to to allocate storage to variable sized chunks.
有时候为变长块分配存储空间更加困难。
There is a solution for that,
这个问题有一个解决方案。
and a solution for that,
以及对此的解决方案，
which is very simple.
这非常简单。
It's about, instead of allocating variable,
这是关于不再分配变量的问题，
says chunks,
说"块"，
you allocate fixed size chunks.
你分配固定大小的块。
And these are called pages.
这些被称为页面。
Every chunk of physical memory is a cable and be the same that it has
每个物理内存块都是一根电缆，并且它们都是相同的。
the same size.
相同大小。
And this can allow you to specially to simplify a lot of things.
这可以让你特别简化很多事情。
For instance,
例如，
how do you handle allocation?
你是如何处理分配的？
One way to handle the allocation is to have a bit vector.
处理分配的一种方法是使用位向量。
And each bit in the vector represents 1 page.
每个位在向量中代表一个页面。
The value zero is that whether that page has been allocated
值为零表示该页面是否已被分配。
from the physical memory,
从物理内存中，
one, if it was allocated.
一，如果它已经被分配了。
So if you want to find a page,
如果你想找到一个页面，
you in physical memory, you can allocate,
你在物理内存中，你可以分配内存。
you just find a zero in this bit vector.
你只需要在这个位向量中找到一个零。
Now, what about the size of the pages?
现在，页面的大小如何？
If the pages are too large?
如果页面太大怎么办？
Again, all pages have the same size.
再次强调，所有页面的大小都相同。
What is the problem?
问题是什么？
What is the problems that pages are too large?
页面过大会导致以下问题：
Waste, spice, internal fragmentation.
浪费、香料、内部碎片化。
Excellent.
非常好。
So I buy beef and edison and and cost of context switching can be higher if
所以我买了牛肉和爱迪生，而且上下文切换的成本可能会更高，如果...
you need to swap that page out.
你需要将那个页面换出。
Right?
对吗？
That's correct.
没错。
But the main thing is about internal fragmentation,
但是主要问题是关于内部碎片化。
because if you think about,
因为如果你仔细思考一下，
if you have this page, you say you have a page of one gigabyte.
如果你有这个页面，你说你有一个1GB的页面。
If your program is only one megabyte,
如果你的程序只有一兆字节大小，
you waste enormous a lot of most of the space.
你浪费了大量的空间。
So you want small babies.
所以你想要小宝宝。
The problem with the small pages,
小页面的问题是，
what is the problem with the small pages?
小页面有什么问题？
Any guess?
有什么猜测吗？
Lots of accounting, more translation is, yes.
很多会计工作，还有更多的翻译工作，是的。
Lots of accounting.
大量的会计工作。
Ii wouldn't say more translations and larger base table.
我不会说更多的翻译和更大的基础表。
You already know about it.
你已经知道了。
Yes.
是的。
But it's accounting is hard like you have to deal with more things.
但是会计学很难，就像你必须处理更多的事情一样。
Let's see.
让我们看看。
Now, how do you do the translation?
现在，你如何进行翻译呢？
But there are no men more translation because in theory, right?
但是在理论上，没有比机器更好的翻译了，对吗？
Because you still need to be every virtual address.
因为你仍然需要处理每个虚拟地址。
You need to translate your physical address.
您需要将您的物理地址翻译成中文。
The little bit of truth of that the higher overhead per translation could be.
每个翻译的开销更高可能是一点点真实的。
But the number of translation is basically the same.
但是翻译的数量基本上是一样的。
Yeah, some cash can be that as well.
是的，有些现金也可以这样。
So how is a translation we spend works with beijing?
那么我们与北京的翻译合作进展如何？
It's very similarly segmentation,
这非常类似于分段。
but with a few differences.
但是有一些不同之处。
So first of all, you have a base table.
首先，你有一个基本表。
And the virtual address, as again, is in two parts.
而虚拟地址，同样也分为两个部分。
We have a virtual patient number and an officer,
我们有一个虚拟患者编号和一个官员。
but there is a difference.
但是有一个区别。
The offset is not added to obeys address.
偏移量没有被添加到目标地址上。
The offset of the address remains the same.
地址的偏移量保持不变。
So is be with translation when you use beijing.
当你在使用北京时，翻译就会起作用。
What happens?
发生了什么事情？
It's only the virtual page part,
只是虚拟页面的部分，
the first field changes.
第一个字段发生了变化。
Right?
对吗？
A virtual page number is replaced by a physical patient.
一个虚拟页号被一个物理页替换。
That's it.
就是这样。
So the same like previously,
和之前一样，
the first speech, in this case,
第一次演讲，在这种情况下，
a virtual page number,
虚拟页号
in the previous case,
在之前的情况下，
was a segment number,
是一个段号。
are going to index in the page table.
将要在页表中进行索引。
But in the page table,
但是在页表中，
what you are going to fail,
你将要失败的是什么？
if I find you have a page number,
如果我发现你有页码，
which is a physical page number,
这是一个物理页号。
you are going to take that physical patient number,
你将要获取那个物理患者编号，
and you are going to concatenate with the offset of the visual address,
然后你将与视觉地址的偏移量连接起来。
the offset of the physical address,
物理地址的偏移量
and the offset of the physical address are the same.
物理地址的偏移量是相同的。
Typical page sizes are between four kilobytes and 16 kilobytes are quite small.
典型的页面大小通常在4KB到16KB之间，属于相当小的范围。
Four kilobytes means what?
四千字节是什么意思？
12 beats you need, 12 beats,
你需要的是12个节拍，12个节拍。
and 16 kilobytes you need.
你需要16千字节。
But another14 bits.
但是另外还有14位。
So if you have even smaller pages,
如果你有更小的页面，
right?
对的？
This is where you see the number.
这是你看到数字的地方。
The problem is a small pages.
问题是页面太小。
So you have a 32 bit address.
所以你有一个32位地址。
You are going to use one by one kilobyte pages,
你将使用逐个千字节页面。
so you can need 10 bits offset.
所以你需要10位偏移量。
It's what you need a 10 bits offset.
你需要一个10位的偏移量。
Therefore, the gift,
因此，这个礼物，
the virtual page number,
虚拟页号
the number of visa is 22 bits,
签证号码为22位。
32-10, 202 bits.
32-10，共计202位。
Therefore, the base table have 4 million century huge.
因此，基表有400万个世纪级巨大的数据。
And just think about if you have 64 bits, others,
想一想，如果你有64位，其他人...
in order to do that, for instance,
为了做到这一点，例如，
you are also going to not allocate space for the maximum size space table.
你还要为最大尺寸的空间表不分配空间。
So you are going to just grow this page table as you add not more pages to it.
所以当你添加新页面时，你只需要扩展这个页表。
Therefore, you are going to have,
因此，你将会有，
in addition to the page table pointer,
除了页表指针之外，
which represents the start of the page table,
这表示页表的起始位置。
also the paste stable size, which is,
还有粘贴的稳定大小，也就是...
as the name implied,
正如名称所示，
the size of the paste table,
粘贴表的大小
which can be increased that you add more tables,
可以通过添加更多的表格来增加。
or as you allocate more pages than you have a lot.
或者当你分配的页面超过你拥有的数量时。
So that afforded your allocate more entries,
这样可以为您分配更多的条目。
you add more entries to the base table.
你需要向基本表中添加更多的条目。
Also, with this page,
此外，使用这个页面，
you are going to have a bunch of bits which represents some.
你将会拥有一堆表示某些东西的位(bit)。
We are going to discuss them or a little bit later.
我们稍后会讨论它们。
Keep in mind about these beats.
记住这些要点。
We are going to give an example,
我们将给出一个例子，
a few slides.
几张幻灯片。
Later.
稍后。
It's a very simple page table.
这是一个非常简单的页表。
You have a four by space.
你有一个四乘四的空间。
It's a trivial example.
这是一个简单的例子。
You have this on the virtual memory.
你在谈论虚拟内存。
You have 4 pages from starting from 04, and 8.
你从04开始有4页，还有8页。
Then you have a page table only with three entries, right?
那么你只有一个只有三个条目的页表，对吗？
Because you have 3 pages in the virtual memo.
因为你在虚拟内存中有3个页面。
Assume that the address space here it has equivalent of eight beats.
假设这里的地址空间相当于八个字节。
So he's 64 bytes.
所以他是64字节。
So the address,
所以这个地址，
if you need for the page table, again, if you have four beats,
如果你需要页面表，再次强调，如果你有四个节拍，
you need only two beats, right?
你只需要两拍，对吗？
To represent 4 bytes,
表示4个字节，
to address 4 bytes.
寻址4个字节。
Therefore, the last two beats represent the offset,
因此，最后两个节拍代表偏移量。
and the first six beats to represent what represent the page number
前六拍代表了页码的含义。
for if you want.
如果你想的话。
A is that the other is zero here.
A 是非零的，另一个是零。
If you want to translate that at zero,
如果你想要零延迟地翻译这个的话，
then the page number of identify the first entry in the table.
然后确定表中第一个条目的页码。
The first century in the table contained four.
表格中的第一列包含了四个。
Now,
现在，
four is a new physical patient numbers who are going to conquer concatinate,
四是一个新的物理患者编号，他们将要征服连接操作。
these four with the offset, which is zero.
这四个的偏移量为零。
You are going to get zero,
你将得到零分。
x one zero.
x one zero 可以翻译为 "十"。
The same thing,
同样的事情，
similar things happen if you want to access the first address,
如果你想访问第一个地址，类似的情况会发生。
the address for the virtual address for the future address for now
现在的虚拟地址对应的未来地址的地址
is going to lead you,
将要引领你，
because the offset which one is going to lead you to the second entry
因为偏移量会将你引导到第二个条目。
in the page table.
在页表中。
The second in being the base table contains threes who
第二个作为基本表格包含了三个人。
are going to concatenate three with zero,
你要将三和零连接起来吗？
which is the offset.
偏移量是多少？
You are going to get to the address zero,
你将要到达地址零。
c physical address, and so forth.
c 物理地址，等等。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Question here?
这里有一个问题吗？
Why were space size issues and between four kilobytes and 16 kilobytes?
为什么空间大小问题在4KB到16KB之间？
This is, again, always a trade off.
这仍然是一个权衡取舍的问题。
The smaller is a table,
越小的是一张桌子。
the smaller the page, the smaller the internal fragmentation,
页面越小，内部碎片越小。
so the less wasted space.
所以尽量减少浪费空间。
However, the smaller the page,
然而，页面越小，
the larger the page tables are.
页面表越大。
So therefore,
因此，
it's much more context switching actually can be more expensive.
实际上，频繁的上下文切换可能会更加昂贵。
Good question.
好问题。
And these are some other translation,
这是一些其他的翻译：
translating the address five.
翻译地址为 "five"。
It's going to translate to all the others,
它将被翻译成其他所有语言。
in this case,
在这种情况下，
is basically 11717.
基本上是11717。
And I think there is another example.
我认为还有另一个例子。
Nine is going to be the same.
九将保持不变。
Sorry.
抱歉。
Previous case, the address six was trans translating to the address one,
之前的情况是，地址六被转换为地址一。
16.
And the second case,
第二种情况是，
the address nine is going to translate to address five,
地址九将被翻译为地址五。
physical address five.
物理地址五。
There is anonymous question asking about if the zero,
有一个匿名问题询问零是否是正数。
x 12345678,
the others could,
其他人可以。
the first 123456 can be the offset.
第一个123456可以作为偏移量。
Now,
现在，
the again,
再次，
the offset are are the last beat in the address.
偏移量是地址中的最后一个字节。
Okay?
好的？
In this particular case, again, the offset,
在这种特殊情况下，再次提到偏移量，
if you look at the first one example here,
如果你看一下这里的第一个例子，
the offset is 10,
偏移量为10。
are the black beats.
这是黑色的节拍。
The page number are the bits,
页号是以位为单位的。
are the red bits.
是红色的位。
So the offset is two, in this case.
在这种情况下，偏移量为2。
And the page number is one.
页面编号是1。
And basic number one selects the second ending the base table,
基本要求一是选择第二个结束基表。
which is three.
这是三。
So it's 11.
所以现在是11点。
And the offset remains 10.
偏移量仍然为10。
Now I have 1110,
现在我有1110。
which is basically e what about sharing?
这基本上是关于共享的问题。
If you want to share a page between processes?
如果你想在进程之间共享一个页面？
These are pretty easy.
这些很简单。
Right?
对吗？
You have each of the processes has its own page label.
每个进程都有自己的页面标签。
If you want to share the same pages,
如果你想共享相同的页面，
then the corresponding entries are going to point to the same physical table.
那么对应的条目将指向同一个物理表。
It very elegant.
非常优雅。
Where is page sharing?
页面共享在哪里？
Yours?
你的？
Generally, region of the processes of every for the processes,
通常情况下，每个进程的区域对于进程来说是独立的。
you have a general region, as you remember.
你有一个大致的区域，就像你记得的那样。
So every process has the same,
所以每个进程都有相同的
all the processes they have to see that you are going to share this code,
所有的进程都必须知道你将要共享这段代码。
the kernel code across all the processes,
所有进程中的内核代码
because the same code is not going to change.
因为相同的代码不会改变。
You can,
你可以。
by the way, this is protected, right?
顺便问一下，这是受保护的，对吧？
Is like the kernel will have.
就像内核会有的那样。
The process only can access at the user level and are talking
该进程只能在用户级别访问并进行通信。
about the kernel region.
关于内核区域。
I'm not talking about kernel region being accessed by the process.
我不是在谈论进程访问内核区域的问题。
I'm talking about the kernel regions associated with the process,
我在谈论与进程相关的内核区域。
which is accessed by the kernel during the context,
在上下文切换期间由内核访问的是什么？
which during different processes running the same binary,
在不同进程运行相同二进制文件时，
you don't need to duplicate that because the code is read only user level libraries,
你不需要复制它，因为代码是只读的用户级库。
like I mentioned,
就像我之前提到的一样，
or even sharing the data between you,
甚至可以在你们之间共享数据，
you can share the data between the processes.
你可以在进程之间共享数据。
You can use a share memory.
你可以使用共享内存。
This is another example.
这是另一个例子。
This is a summary of beijing.
这是北京的概述。
On the left hand side,
在左侧
you have the virtual memory view.
你有虚拟内存视图。
On the right hand side.
在右侧。
You have the physical memory view.
你拥有物理内存视图。
In the middle, you have the base table.
在中间，你有基本表。
You see that many entries in the tables are now,
你会发现表格中有许多条目现在是空的。
but this is a full page table.
但这是一个完整的页表。
And here we are assuming and eight beats address.
在这里，我们假设使用八位地址。
And now the offset are the last three beats.
现在偏移量是最后三拍。
So the base size, it's about three,
基本大小，大约是三。
it's 8 bytes.
它是8个字节。
And the patient number is 5 bits.
患者编号为5位。
You are going to have 2.5.
你将会得到2.5。
You have 72 entries in the page table up to.
你的页表中有72个条目。
Okay.
好的。
Now, the one thing,
现在，有一件事，
and on the right hand side,
在右侧，
you have, again, like the physical memory.
你再次拥有了物理内存。
One thing here, I just want to show you.
有一件事情，我只是想给你看一下。
And i'm so earlier on,
而且我来得很早，
I said that the stack,
我说的是栈，
how the stack and the heap grows here.
在这里，堆栈和堆是如何增长的。
Now, the stack again, grows downwards.
现在，栈再次向下增长。
So gonna go grows,
所以要继续成长，
going to lower addresses.
向较低的地址移动。
And you see here,
你看到这里，
the stack,
栈
it's on the right hand side.
它在右侧。
And with with what I represented here is a gray,
我在这里所代表的是一个灰色的东西。
the pages which they are all the allocate,
这些页面都已经被分配了。
only the pages which are white are not allocated yet.
只有白色的页面尚未分配。
So let's see what happens and how you are going to grow the stock.
那么让我们看看会发生什么，以及你将如何增加股票的增长。
Now,
现在，
the problem is that let's say that I want to grow the stack by 2 pages,
问题是，假设我想将栈增加2页，
I decided to grow the stack by 2 pages in the virtual memory.
我决定在虚拟内存中将栈增加2页。
The virtual memory, I can very conveniently grow the style,
虚拟内存非常方便地可以扩展容量。
because I have enough space in the virtual memory.
因为我在虚拟内存中有足够的空间。
However, is a physical memory.
然而，它是一种物理内存。
If I am going to try to grow it,
如果我打算尝试种植它，
I can allocate page.
我可以分配页面。
You can allocate another page.
你可以分配另一页。
Maybe you have only room for another page there if you want to locate
如果你想要定位，可能只有另一页的空间。
continuously that the pages to the stack.
不断地将页面压入堆栈。
But the point is a page a with a translation that these pages
但关键是一个页面与这些页面的翻译
do not need to be allocated continuously.
不需要连续分配。
Right?
对吗？
Therefore, the only thing you can do,
因此，你唯一能做的事情是，
the only thing you need to do,
你需要做的唯一事情是，
you need to find the room for two other pages.
你需要找到另外两页的空间。
And you are going to allocate these pages for the stock.
你将为股票分配这些页面。
But again, they don't need to be contiguous, right?
但是再说一遍，它们不需要是连续的，对吗？
Whatever is contiguous in the virtual memory,
无论在虚拟内存中是连续的，
doesn't need to be contiguous in the physical.
在物理上不需要连续。
Now,
现在，
the biggest problem is the challenge,
最大的问题是挑战。
the type of table size.
表的大小类型。
If you in the simplest version,
如果你采用最简单的版本，
in the simple instantiation,
在简单实例化中，
in the simplest implementation,
在最简单的实现中，
the type of size,
大小的类型
but if it's equal with a number of babies in the virtual memory,
但如果它等于虚拟内存中的婴儿数量，
and this can be absolutely huge.
而且这可能是非常巨大的。
Let's give take an example.
让我们举个例子。
You have 32 beats address space,
你有32位的地址空间。
you have four gigabytes at others,
你在其他地方有四个千兆字节。
mutual address space.
共享地址空间。
These are just a unit for you to remember.
这些只是一些你需要记住的单元。
The one things to remember here.
这里需要记住的一件事是。
And one confusion i've all seen often is that when you are talking
我经常看到的一个困惑是当你谈论时
about the memory,
关于内存，
we are talking about the power of two units.
我们正在讨论二进制单位的幂次。
One kilobyte is ten to power ten,
一千字节是10的10次方。
one megabyte to power ten,
一兆字节的十次方
and gigabyte to power set.
将字节转换为位。
I when we are talking about bandwidth,
当我们谈论带宽时，
and how much capacity network capacity we are talking in power of that?
我们在讨论的网络容量是多少功率？
1 kilobyte or 1 kilobit.
1千字节或1千比特。
It's 1,000 bits,
这是1,000比特。
one gigabyte,
一千兆字节
one gigabit represent,
一千兆位表示，
but it's1 billion bits.
但这是10亿比特。
So now assume the typical pay size is four kilobytes.
现在假设典型的页大小为四千字节。
It's to power them.
这是为了给它们供电。
We need ten beats for to address any byte in a 4 kilobyte page.
我们需要十个时钟周期来访问4千字节页面中的任意一个字节。
So there are four.
所以有四个。
Sorry, we need to have what i'm talking about.
抱歉，我们需要明确你所说的是什么。
If the page is four kilobytes,
如果页面大小为四千字节，
this means to power 12.
这意味着乘以12的幂。
Therefore, I need 12 beats to address any bite within a page.
因此，我需要12个节拍来寻址页面中的任何字节。
So the offset is stern beats.
所以偏移量是严格的节拍。
And therefore,
因此，
if the offset mister beats,
如果偏移量错误
the page number,
页码
it's 30.
是30。
2-12 is 20 bits.
2-12 是 20 位。
Now,
现在，
the base table size can have as big as 4 megabytes.
基本表的大小可以达到4兆字节。
Right?
对吗？
Why is 4 megabytes?
为什么是4兆字节？
Because each of the entry in the page table needs to have 20 bits.
因为页表中的每个条目都需要有20位。
Then you are also going to have some other,
那么你还会有其他的任务。
like you see some other flags associated.
就像你看到其他相关的标志一样。
So you have 30° for each end.
每个端点都有30°。
So it's 4 bytes,
所以它是4个字节。
and you have to power 20 entries.
你需要为20个条目提供电源。
So it's 4 megabytes the top.
所以最大是4兆字节。
This was a lot of memory.
这占用了很多内存。
Now think about this was in the past,
现在想想这是过去的事情了，
and you have said little bit as the standard.
你说的有一点是正确的。
But now the standard is 64 bits.
但现在的标准是64位。
There is no way, right?
没有办法，对吗？
If you try to do the same thing here,
如果你在这里尝试做同样的事情，
you are going to have 30 extra bytes,
你将会有额外的30个字节。
which is only for the pace table.
这仅适用于页表。
Actually,
实际上，
you don't have enough physical memory for that physical to store
你的物理内存不足以存储该物理页。
that the pace label.
那是速度标签。
This is really a lot of space.
这真的是很大的空间。
What is the solution here?
这里的解决方案是什么？
By the way, all this space is empty.
顺便说一下，这个空间都是空的。
Most of this, no, not always,
大部分情况下，不，不总是。
most of the space is empty,
大部分的空间是空的。
because they don't have as many base tables,
因为它们没有那么多基本表格，
but I do have very few space tables,
但是我确实有很少的空间表格。
right?
对的？
Which are actually allocated a so this is a big problem.
实际上已经分配了这么多，这是一个大问题。
And we are looking out for a solution,
我们正在寻找一个解决方案，
a little bit of a discussion about base table before going forward.
在继续之前，先简单讨论一下基本表。
So what do you need to switch on the page label?
那么你需要打开页面标签吗？
What do you need to do this?
你需要做什么来完成这个任务？
When the context switch happens?
上下文切换发生在什么时候？
What do we need to do?
我们需要做什么？
You have a page for the table point as the page label pointer,
你有一个页面用作表格指针的页面标签。
the beginning of the page table,
页表的开始部分，
the limit,
限制
the size of the page table.
页面表的大小。
Again,
再次，
remember about the dual mode operation.
记住双模式操作。
And because you these space tables can be only
因为你这些空间表只能是这样的
modified and accessed by the kernel,
由内核修改和访问
you cannot let an application access the space labels,
你不能让一个应用程序访问空间标签。
because then they can change the page table,
因为这样他们就可以更改页表。
and they can.to anywhere to any other address,
它们可以到任何地方，到任何其他地址。
including the kennel or the address of another applications.
包括狗舍或其他应用程序的地址。
And now let's look at the pros and cons.
现在让我们来看一下利与弊。
On the pro side.
在正面方面。
It's a very simple memory allocation.
这是一个非常简单的内存分配。
Remember, you have a bit vector in zero or one,
记住，你有一个由零或一组成的位向量。
whether the page is allocated or not in the physical memory.
判断页面是否在物理内存中分配。
The bit vector contains 1 bit for each physical,
位向量包含每个物理页的1个位。
for each page in the physical memo,
对于物理内存中的每一页，
easy to share the cons we seen.
很容易分享我们所看到的缺点。
The other space is very sparse.
另一个空间非常稀疏。
The base table can be huge.
基本表可能非常庞大。
It's again, if the base table is peace big,
如果基表非常大的话，
then you need also probably the context which you cannot keep all the time
那么你可能还需要上下文，但你不可能一直记得所有的上下文信息。
in the memory.
在内存中。
If the process is painful,
如果这个过程是痛苦的，
is that there is a base level of a process.
这是指进程的基本级别。
If the process was is now switched off and is no longer using the cpu you
如果进程现在已经关闭并且不再使用CPU，那么
may want,
可能想要
it was preempted.
它被抢占了。
You may want to take the page table of that process and swap on the disk.
你可能想要获取该进程的页表并将其交换到磁盘上。
But if that is large,
但如果那个很大的话，
then the overhead is very large.
那么开销就非常大。
So the deal we are here,
所以我们在这里的交易是
the best table,
最好的桌子
the paging as a technique,
分页作为一种技术，
it's elegant solution,
这是一个优雅的解决方案。
very simple to implement,
非常简单实现。
provides low internal fragmentation.
提供低内部碎片化。
If the pages are small.
如果页面很小。
On the downside,
不过，
the problem we encounter is when we have big,
我们遇到的问题是当我们有大型的数据时，
it is because the page tables can be huge.
这是因为页表可能非常庞大。
So what is the solution?
那么解决方案是什么呢？
Right?
对吗？
The solution is you repair that the same technique I do like you recursive,
解决方案是修复与我相同的技术，就像你递归一样。
they do it.
他们做了。
It's multilevel beijing.
这是多层次的北京。
Right?
对吗？
Look, if the page labels are very large,
如果页面标签非常大的话，
then why don't we have a base table for that base table?
那为什么我们不为那个基本表再建立一个基本表呢？
Right?
对吗？
Or you can combine painting segmentation?
或者你可以结合绘画分割技术。
These are the two solutions.
这是两个解决方案。
A segment mapping, you are going to have segments.
段映射，你将拥有段。
And in the segments,
在分段中，
you are going to have,
你将要拥有，
you page the segments,
你分页了段落。
and then in the page table as you are going to the page tables.
然后在访问页表时，你会进入页表。
And let's look about how this is work.
让我们来看看这是如何工作的。
As a core remembers that the page table is a map
作为一个核心，记住页表是一个映射。
between the virtual page number and the physical page.
虚拟页号和物理页号之间的对应关系。
This is where it is.
这就是它的位置。
A simple page table is just a look up table.
一个简单的页表就是一个查找表。
Vpn, the virtual page number.
VPN，即虚拟页号。
It's an index in this table,
这是表中的一个索引。
which contains a physical page number.
其中包含一个物理页号。
By the way, what are the map structures?
顺便问一下，地图结构是什么？
When you think of?
你在想什么？
There are many of them, trees, hash table, and so forth.
有很多种数据结构，例如树、哈希表等等。
But obviously, these are more complicated,
但显然，这些更加复杂。
means higher overhead,
意味着更高的开销
even though they can have slower storage overhead.
尽管它们可能会有较慢的存储开销。
The beautiful things about the very stable is very quick to access it.
非常稳定的优点之一是非常快速地访问它。
Right?
对吗？
It's just a needless.
这只是多余的。
If you use the trees and hash tables,
如果你使用树和哈希表，
and we'll see about that.
我们会看看的。
They are much more space efficient.
它们在空间利用上更高效。
You don't need to maintain all the entries,
你不需要维护所有的条目，
which for it, there is no table.
对于它来说，没有表格。
But accessing those is much more expensive.
但是访问这些的成本要高得多。
There is a trade off here.
这里存在一个权衡。
One simple solution is like we alluded, we mentioned,
一个简单的解决方案就像我们所暗示的，我们提到的那样。
is to have to do the problem of having very big page tables is to page
拥有非常大的页表是处理页的问题之一。
these page tables.
这些页表。
Basically, here is a two level page labels.
基本上，这是一个两级页标签。
And here is that instead of now,
而这是代替现在的。
the address has three fields at the end of the offset, like before,
地址在偏移量的末尾有三个字段，与之前一样。
no difference here.
这里没有任何区别。
But what was previously corresponding to the page number?
之前对应于页号的是什么？
Now you split into two fields,
现在你分成了两个领域，
which corresponds to virtual page numbers of page indexes for the two level
这对应于两级页索引的虚拟页号。
pages.
页面。
The first ten beats,
前十拍
in this case,
在这种情况下，
represents a virtual p one index in the index,
在索引中表示一个虚拟页的索引。
in the first level table,
在第一级表中，
page table.
页表。
This is going to take,
这可能需要一些时间。
you is going to contain an address to
你将包含一个地址
a page containing the page table entries at the second level.
一个包含第二级页表项的页面。
Okay?
好的？
In order to compute now the entire physical address,
为了现在计算整个物理地址，
use a few an index to find the address of the page containing
使用几个索引来查找包含页面的地址
the physical page number,
物理页号
which is stored in the second level.
这个数据存储在第二级。
This physical page number is going to be concatenate with the offset like before.
这个物理页号将会和偏移量像之前一样连接起来。
And now you have the physical address.
现在你有了物理地址。
Okay?
好的？
It's the same thing.
这是同样的事情。
The only difference is that now you split the physical page number into a part,
唯一的区别是现在你将物理页号分成了两部分，
which is going to index into a page table,
将要索引到一个页表中的地址，
first level page table,
一级页表
which contains the address of a second level page table.
其中包含了一个二级页表的地址。
And the second field in this page number is going to index
这个页面编号的第二个字段将用作索引。
in this second level page table.
在这个二级页表中。
And at that entry,
在那个入口处，
corresponding entry are going to hand physical page now.
对应的条目现在将要分配物理页面。
And you can have many moral levels.
你可以有许多道德层次。
Now, these are some announcements.
现在，这是一些公告。
We are just 15 minutes before the class ends,
我们离课程结束只剩下15分钟了。
but here are some announcements.
但是这里有一些公告。
We release a midterm scores,
我们发布了期中考试成绩。
and please check piazza for degrading policies.
请查看 Piazza 上的降级政策。
I think you did quite well,
我认为你做得相当不错，
the scores and the distribution is very much in line with that of the past midterms.
成绩和分布与过去的期中考试非常一致。
In the recent years,
近年来，
the project two design documentary member is due by this at the end
项目二的设计文档成员截止日期是在本周末。
of this friday.
本周五。
The homeless three is due on sunday at the end of the day.
无家可归的三人组的截止日期是周日，截止时间是当天晚上。
If you want an extra credit.,
如果你想要额外的学分，
please feel free is a mid semester survey and check on piazza for details.
请随意填写中期调查，并在Piazza上查看详细信息。
So it's free.
所以它是免费的。
Three extra credit.
三个额外学分。
The next lecture,
下一堂课，
i'll be out of town at nathan pemperton with a senior phd student,
我将和一位高级博士生一起去纳森·彭珀顿镇出差。
which you expect boston architectures and systems is going to beach this class.
你期望波士顿的架构和系统将在这门课上取得突破。
He's a fantastic teacher.
他是一位非常棒的老师。
Fun.
有趣。
I really urge you to attend his lecture.
我真的强烈建议你参加他的讲座。
He is there going to be a lot more fun than my lectures?
他在那里会比我的讲座更有趣吗？
He's a great presenter.
他是一个很棒的演讲者。
I remember that iii mentioned to you now that in a page table entry,
我记得iii现在向你提到，在页表项中，
besides the besides of physical page number,
除了物理页号之外，
we are going also to have some bits.
我们也将拥有一些位。
And here is an example.
这里是一个例子。
Let's take our previous examples.
让我们来看一下之前的例子。
If you are going to have an offside offset of the or you have a 32 beats address,
如果你要设置一个偏移量为offside的地址，或者你有一个32位的地址，
the offset is 12 bits,
偏移量为12位。
so the physical page number is 20 bits.
物理页号是20位。
So now,
现在，
in a base table,
在一个基本表中，
what you need the physical page number,
你需要物理页号。
which is this 20 bits.
这是20位的二进制数。
So what about the rest of the rest of 12 bits?
那剩下的12位是什么情况？
For the rest of the 12 beats?
剩下的12拍呢？
You are going to have a bunch of flags which are used.
你将会有一堆被使用的标志。
They have different use that they can use it in different ways.
它们有不同的用途，可以以不同的方式使用。
But here it's an example.
但是这里有一个例子。
And this is from intel architecture.
这是来自英特尔架构的。
So these are examples about this beats.
这些是关于这个节拍的例子。
And we are going to start from the this significant means zero is p this
我们将从这个重要的意义开始，零被表示为p。
is present.
已经存在。
It's the same as valid.
它与"valid"是相同的。
Is a page present in physical memory or not?
一个页面是否存在于物理内存中？
W write a book.
我写一本书。
Can you write on this page or not?
你能在这个页面上写吗？
If it's zero, then it's read only its user accessible,
如果为零，则只读取其用户可访问的内容。
this page accessible only by user.
此页面仅限用户访问。
Pwt page write transparent.
PWT（页面写入透明）
This is related with a cash.
这与现金有关。
Typical you have cash is to to reduce the latency to access the data.
典型的缓存的作用是为了减少访问数据的延迟。
Right?
对吗？
When you have caches a problem,
当你遇到缓存问题时，
the question is about how you are going to update the physical memory,
问题是关于您如何更新物理内存的。
the data in the physical memory.
物理内存中的数据。
Right?
对吗？
There are two ways here we are going to learn.
我们将学习两种方法。
But one way is that whenever we are going to access and we
但有一种方法是，每当我们要访问时，我们可以
are going to write to the cache and modify the data,
将要写入缓存并修改数据。
we are also going to modify the data in the physical memory.
我们还将修改物理内存中的数据。
And this is page writes, transparent,
这是一个透明的页面。
bcd space cash disabled.
BCD空间现金禁用。
You cannot catch the pages.
你无法捕捉页面。
A its access page has been accessed recently.
最近访问了它的访问页面。
This is used also for cashing.
这也用于缓存。
But I think it's accessed recently.
但我认为它最近被访问过。
And the next two is the same, first of all, cash.
接下来的两个是一样的，首先是现金。
You want to know whether the pages access recently and whether is dirty
你想知道最近访问的页面以及是否是脏页。
was written,
被写成了,
and the physical memory associated with physical memory was not updated.
与物理内存相关联的物理内存没有被更新。
So you need to know about that.
所以你需要了解这个。
And then you are going,
然后你要走了
we may decide to page that to this is.
我们可能决定将这个页面换到那个位置。
Okay, how do I say?
好的，我该怎么说呢？
So these two beats,
所以这两个节拍，
the only thing you need to know now are used when deciding what page
在决定页面时，你现在需要知道的唯一事情是什么。
to swap out of the
换出（swap out）
memory to make the room for me pages.
为我腾出内存页的空间。
Fundamentally,
从根本上说，
you do not want to swap up a page of a process which will be accessed india.
你不想交换一个将要在印度访问的进程的页面。
I it's a question.
这是一个问题。
The pcd means,
PCD 是指 "Pre-charge delay"，即预充电延迟。
the question is obesity means it's about obesity means the pcd means
问题是肥胖意味着什么，它是关于肥胖意味着什么的，PCD是什么意思。
that the page is not cached.
该页面未被缓存。
Again, the reason you may choose to not cash a page is that, for instance,
再次，你选择不缓存页面的原因可能是，例如，
in multiprocessor systems,
在多处理器系统中，
multicore systems,
多核系统
when you have concurrency on on the same page,
当你在同一页上有并发时，
you have a page with a shared to different processes,
你有一个被不同进程共享的页面。
which run on different processors.
运行在不同处理器上。
And they can concurrently access that page.
他们可以同时访问该页面。
And if you want to update the page,
如果你想要更新页面，
if it's cashed each process in each process of cash,
如果每个进程的每个进程都被缓存了现金，
then you have a cache coherence problem.
那么你遇到了缓存一致性问题。
If you want to simplify that problem,
如果你想简化这个问题，
if you want to remove that problem,
如果你想解决那个问题，
you can say this page is never going to be cash.
你可以说这个页面永远不会被缓存。
Example of how to use pd invalid pd es is that it's, again,
使用pd invalid pd es的示例是，再次强调它是无效的。
even this one can in the imply different things and the operating system
即使这个词可以暗示不同的含义，但在操作系统中可以有不同的解释。
besides how to use these flags
除了如何使用这些标志之外
once.
一次。
And one we use is that which I didn't mention is that the address space
我们使用的另一个是我没有提到的地址空间。
is actually not valid,
实际上是无效的。
right?
对的吗？
It doesn't is not allocated.
它没有被分配。
But another way is basically say the page director,
但另一种方式基本上是指页面导向器。
it's that page,
那个页面是这样的，
it's not in the memo, it's on the disk.
这不在备忘录中，而是在磁盘上。
Right?
对吗？
In that case, you need it a it's a a it's a trap to the operating system,
在这种情况下，你需要将它作为一个陷阱传递给操作系统。
exception.
异常。
It results into a trap to the operating system.
这会对操作系统造成陷阱。
And the operating system is going to figure out where is the biggest start,
操作系统将会找出最大的起始位置。
and it's going to bring it to memory.
然后它将把它加载到内存中。
This is going to be used by the main page.
这将被主页使用。
We are going to learn about that.
我们将要学习这个。
Another use here is about copy and write for the pd basically,
另一个用途是基本上关于页表的复制和写入。
when you fork,
当你进行fork操作时，
remember that the fork,
记住，fork操作
when you fork a process, a fork process copy,
当你fork一个进程时，会创建一个副本进程，
actually the parent process, right?
实际上是父进程，对吗？
It has everything.
它拥有一切。
And now the question is that do you want to copy it right away?
现在的问题是，你是否想立即复制它？
Right?
对吗？
Are you going to copy everything?
你打算抄全部内容吗？
And it's not smart to do it, because,
这样做是不明智的，因为，
for instance,
例如，
the code of the process of the parent process is the same code.
父进程的代码和子进程的代码是相同的。
You are the child process is going to execute.
你是将要执行的子进程。
The code is read only, so you can only to copy.
这段代码是只读的，所以你只能复制。
But the same is also true about the data.
但是对于数据来说也是一样的。
But I I do want to copy to move that to copy the data from the process
但是我确实想要复制并移动数据从该进程中。
at a space to the child at the space.
在一个空间给孩子留出空间。
The answer there is that only if the child ideally only of the child access,
答案是，只有当子进程仅限于子进程访问时。
right?
对的？
And write it, right?
是的，需要将其写下来。
So when that's what,
那么，当那个时候，
so initially,
所以最初，
when you are going to create,
你打算什么时候创建？
if you because you want to reduce the overhead to create at the forecast process,
如果你因为想要减少创建预测过程的开销而这样做，
the four process can share the entire address that via address space
这四个进程可以共享整个通过地址空间的地址。
to the parent process.
给父进程。
So the reads are very,
所以读取操作非常的，
there are going to the same memory is memory efficient is fast,
将相同的数据存储在同一块内存中既节省内存又快速。
right before.
就在之前。
But then the only one you can start doing it is when you write it.
但是你能开始做的唯一时间是在你写它的时候。
So when you write a page, now,
现在，当你写一个页面时，
only now you are going to create a copy of that page for the child.
现在你要为孩子创建该页面的副本。
And now the child can write and read from that copy.
现在孩子可以从那个副本中写入和读取数据。
But as long as you want to read,
只要你想读，
you can read from the same memory, physical memory,
你可以从同一块物理内存中读取数据。
which is shared a a with a balance.
这是一个共享的账户，具有余额。
Another use case here.
这里还有另一个使用案例。
It's a zero field on demand.
这是一个零场需求。
So say,
所以说，
you allocate,
你分配
say, ten gigabytes of memory and you want to initialize the zero.
假设你有十个千兆字节的内存，并且你想要将其初始化为零。
Just that it initialization can take seconds many seconds.
只是初始化可能需要几秒钟甚至更长时间。
Just to do this initialization,
只是为了进行这个初始化操作，
you don't want to pay the overhead,
你不想支付额外开销。
then when you are going to order allocation,
那么当你要进行分配时，
instead of you can do zero fill on demand.
可以改为你可以按需进行零填充。
The os now that this pages needs to be zero,
操作系统现在需要将该页面清零。
but initially doesn't make them zero.
但最初并不将它们设为零。
It may seem zero only on your axis average.
在你的坐标轴平均值上，它可能看起来是零。
And that's perfectly fine,
这完全没问题，
because you amortize zeroing it or even better,
因为你将其摊销为零，甚至更好的是，
maybe the application is not going to ever touch every bite,
也许应用程序永远不会接触到每一个字节。
which is allocating these standard devices.
是谁在分配这些标准设备。
Right?
对吗？
Say this, again, some smart ways to use this video.
再说一遍，一些使用这个视频的聪明方法。
So sharing with multiple level pages,
所以多级页面共享，
sorry.
对不起。
Oops.
哎呀。
You can see here,
你可以在这里看到，
you have two processes.
你有两个进程。
You have this each process has its own base table at rt
每个进程都有自己的基表在运行时。
the first level page,
第一级页
you can see for each process,
你可以查看每个进程的信息。
it's pointed from you have the base table pointer for employees, part,
你需要为员工和零件的基本表指针进行指向。
base table pointer, crime,
基本表指针，犯罪，
for the two base labels,
对于这两个基本标签，
different base labels,
不同的基本标签
first level base tables.
第一级基本表。
Each of them, they have point to second level page tables.
每个页面表都指向二级页表。
And what you can see here that some of the second level page tables are shared.
在这里你可以看到一些二级页表是共享的。
Obviously, all the pages to each entries in the shared space tables,
显然，共享空间表中的每个条目都有对应的页面。
.2are also shared.
还有0.2也是共享的。
Right?
对吗？
And finally,
最后，
you remember,
你记得吗？
I we started with this solving this problem that the page tables
我们开始解决这个问题，即页面表的问题。
can become extremely large.
可以变得非常庞大。
If we have,
如果我们有的话，
and many of the entries are from these huge base tables are now,
现在，许多条目来自这些巨大的基础表。
so contains no Information.
所以不包含任何信息。
And we said that the two level page table is going to solve that,
我们说过，双级页表将解决这个问题。
address that problem,
解决这个问题，
or at least alleviate that problem.
或者至少缓解这个问题。
Here is an example.
这是一个例子。
If you remember, this is an example,
如果你还记得的话，这是一个例子。
and let me just try to go back here.
让我试着回到这里。
This is a previous example.
这是一个之前的例子。
So this is the example which are going to have,
这是我们将要使用的示例。
if you can see you,
如果你能看到自己，
this was a 111 level table.
这是一个111级别的表格。
So you have, I think, 32 entries,
所以你有，我想，32个条目。
many of these centuries are now.
许多世纪现在已经过去了。
Right?
对吗？
This is a corresponding example.
这是一个相应的例子。
That's this is a corresponding example you can see.
这是一个相应的例子，你可以看到。
And you can count.
而且你会数数。
You have much fuels.
你有很多燃料。
It requires to appear less storage for storing these space labels.
需要减少存储这些空间标签所需的空间。
Right?
对吗？
And certainly, you have much more fewer malignants.
而且，你确实有更少的恶性疾病。
Let's continue.
让我们继续吧。
We have just a few more minutes.
我们只剩下几分钟了。
And this also tells you about how the translation is done.
这也告诉你关于翻译是如何进行的。
In this particular case,
在这种特定情况下，
we have for the first page, the level page table,
我们有第一页的级别页表。
we use three beats for the second level two beats,
我们在第二级使用三拍，第二级使用两拍。
and for the offset 3 bits.
对于偏移量的3位。
So in the best case, an article,
在最理想的情况下，一篇文章，
the size of the page tables is a number of pages used by the program
页面表的大小是程序使用的页面数量。
in the spiritual memory.
在精神记忆中。
Unlike the previous case,
与之前的情况不同，
in which the number of pages was the one available in the physical memory,
在这种情况下，页面的数量与物理内存中可用的页面数量相同。
the price to pay here is that you have one more additional memory access,
这里需要付出的代价是多了一个额外的内存访问。
right?
对的？
Because they need to do index on both space labels,
因为他们需要在两个空间标签上进行索引。
advanced level.
高级水平。
How about about segments and pages?
关于段和页，你是想了解什么？
Right?
对吗？
This is another way to do it, right?
这是另一种方法，对吗？
Like we have two level tables.
就像我们有两个级别的表格一样。
But another way to sell to solve similar problems is have to combine
但是解决类似问题的另一种方法是将其结合起来销售。
segmentation with spaging.
分段与分页结合的分段分页机制。
In this case, again,
在这种情况下，再次，
you have the address is split into three fields,
你的地址被分成了三个字段。
but the first field represent a segment number.
但是第一个字段表示段号。
The second field represents a virtual page number,
第二个字段表示虚拟页号。
resumes a segment,
恢复一个段落
and then you have the offset.
然后你有偏移量。
It's a very similar approach.
这是一个非常相似的方法。
It's again here.
又是我。
What do you need to save and store?
您需要保存和存储什么内容？
When contact switching?
什么时候进行上下文切换？
You need to store the segment table.
你需要存储段表。
You need to start the page table for that process.
你需要为该进程启动页表。
How do you share the data across different segments?
如何在不同的段之间共享数据？
When you have these both segments and pay and Beijing?
当你有这两个片段并支付了费用，你会在北京吗？
It's the same very similar way that I you are going to have
这是非常相似的方式，你将会拥有它。
from two different processes.
来自两个不同的进程。
They can share the pages by simply having the base
他们可以通过简单地拥有基址来共享页面。
by sharing the segment,
通过共享段，
right?
是的，正确的。
If you understand a bunch of pages,
如果你能理解一堆页面，
you are going to put all these pages in the same segment,
你将把所有这些页面放在同一个段中。
then you are going to share the same very soon.
那么你很快就会分享相同的东西了。
Let me do this one last slide,
让我做最后一张幻灯片。
and then I am going to stop here.
然后我就要停在这里了。
When you have multilevel translation pages,
当你有多级翻译页面时，
what are the pros and cons?
优点和缺点是什么？
Okay?
好的？
The big PRO is that you get to is much less space for the page labels.
最大的优点是你可以为页面标签节省很多空间。
Right?
对吗？
That's it.
就是这样。
The phone number, the Beijing in themselves,
电话号码是北京的
they have the big advantage that it's fixed size.
它们的一个巨大优势是固定大小。
So they retain to some simplicity,
所以它们保持了一些简单性，
you have no external fragmentation,
你没有外部碎片化。
have only internal fragmentation.
只有内部碎片化。
The cause is that the page tables can be huge,
原因是页表可能非常庞大，
because they need to be continuous because you need to indexing with them.
因为它们需要连续，你需要使用它们进行索引。
Therefore,
因此，
you need to have multiple level of labels in order to get
你需要有多个层级的标签才能实现。
the memory allocation with the two to get
使用两个进行内存分配
efficient memory allocation for the page tables.
高效的页面表内存分配。
But the big problem is that now you need to have multiple look UPS for translation,
但是现在的一个大问题是你需要进行多次查找来进行翻译。
because you need to look to have a look up for each page level.
因为你需要为每个页面级别进行查找。
Let's stop here again.
让我们再次停下来。
Please attend Nathan lecture on Thursday,
请在周四参加Nathan的讲座。
and i'll see you next Monday.
我下周一见。
Thanks.
谢谢。
So we are done.
我们完成了。
Let me just some recording.
让我录一下。